Hello and welcome to section 7
您好，欢迎来到第7节
of lesson 2. Here, we're going to discuss
第2课的内容。在这里，我们将讨论
the Optional class which is new class that was introduced in JDK 8
可选类，它是JDK 8中引入的新类
A lot of it is to do with how we process streams the results from streams
这很大程度上与我们处理流的方式有关
but it's also very useful
但这也很有用
in many other places as well as we'll see.
在许多其他地方以及我们将看到的地方。
The problem we have is what happens
我们遇到的问题是发生了什么
when we've got no values and because we're dealing with objects
当我们没有价值并且因为我们正在处理对象时
if we have no value, we have null reference.
如果没有值，则为空引用。
so it's effectively a reference to object that is not initialized.
因此它实际上是对未初始化对象的引用。
So we've dealt with nulls in the past. We know what nulls are know how we get them.
因此，我们过去处理过null。我们知道空值是什么，我们知道如何得到它们。
And he's the kind of problem we have to face:
他是我们必须面对的问题：
let's say that I've got a piece of code where
假设我有一段代码
I have some data that I'm calling from a GPS receiver
我有一些从GPS接收器拨打的数据
and what I want to get is the direction
而我想要得到的是方向
of the latitude associated with the position that I'm reading.
与我正在读取的位置相关的纬度。
And I would typically chain together some method calls
我通常会将一些方法调用链接在一起
to say that what I want is the direction from the latitude,
说我想要的是纬度方向，
which comes from the position, which comes from a GPS data. All well and good.
来自位置，来自GPS数据。一切都很好。
The problem with this is that that will work
问题在于这将起作用
so long as neither gpsData
只要没有gpsData
getPosition or getLatitude return a null.
getPosition或getLatitude返回null。
Because if any of those three things return a null
因为如果这三件事中的任何一个返回null
then I'm getting a nullPointException because going to try to call a method
那我得到一个nullPointException因为要尝试调用一个方法
through a null reference. And I can't do that-
通过空引用。我不能那样做-
Gives me nullPointerException. So this
给我nullPointerException。所以这
is not the most robust way writing code if I can't guarantee that GPSdata
如果我不能保证GPSdata是最健壮的代码编写方式
is not null and the getPosition and getLatitude will not
不为null，getPosition和getLatitude不会
return a null. Let's rewrite the same code
返回一个空值。让我们重写相同的代码
and make it completely safe from a nullPointerExceptions point of view.
并从nullPointerExceptions的角度使其完全安全。
This is what we end up with. We start off by assigning
这就是我们最终得到的结果。我们从分配开始
a direction to be unknown, so we have a definite value for that.
一个未知的方向，因此我们有一个确定的值。
Then we look at gpsData, we test to see if it’s null,
然后我们看一下gpsData，我们测试一下是否为空，
if that’s not null, we get the position
如果不为空，我们得到位置
from gpsData.getPosition. Then we test to see if that is null. If it's not null
来自gpsData.getPosition。然后我们测试一下是否为空。如果不为空
we get the latitude from p.getLatitude.
我们从p.getLatitude获得纬度。
And then we test that the latitude is not null. If the latitude is not null, then we can call
然后我们测试纬度不为空。如果纬度不为空，那么我们可以调用
direction from that and get our result. So this is all good.
方向，并获得我们的结果。所以这一切都很好。
Problem is, that we need a better way of doing this.
问题是，我们需要一种更好的方法来做到这一点。
And when we look at the streams API
当我们看流API时
what we often find we've already seen this when we talk about the terminal operations,
在谈论终端操作时，我们经常会发现这一点，
is that things like min and max, they...
是像最小和最大这样的东西，它们...
If we have no elements on the InputStream
如果我们在InputStream上没有元素
what do we return as a result? I mean, we could return 0 as the min
结果返回什么？我的意思是，我们可以返回0作为最小值
or 0 as the max. But that doesn't actually make sense because we may not be comparing
或最大为0但这实际上没有任何意义，因为我们可能没有进行比较
based on numerical values. And
基于数值。和
so we have a situation where we would typically return a null.
因此，我们通常会返回null。
But that becomes then difficult because if we want to process that
但这变得困难，因为如果我们要处理
further, we run into problems where then we got a test to see if it's a null, if it's
此外，我们遇到了问题，然后我们进行了测试以查看它是否为null，是否为null。
not then we went to do various things, and and so.
然后我们去做各种事情，等等。
To get around that, we've introduced this new class
为了解决这个问题，我们引入了这个新类
called an optional. And an Optional has a type parameter
称为可选。并且Optional具有类型参数
T. Effectively what an Optional
T.实际上是什么可选
is... Its contain are for another
是...它包含另一个
object reference and that reference
对象引用和那个引用
can either be null or it can be pointing at a real
可以为null或可以指向实数
object. So you can think of it,
宾语。所以你可以考虑一下
as like a stream which has either 0
就像流的其中一个为0
or 1 elements in it. 0 elements if the reference the object is null
或其中的1个元素。 0个元素（如果引用对象为null）
one element if the object
如果对象是一个元素
reference is valid. There will be 1 element
参考有效。将有1个元素
in that stream will be the reference to the object. The good thing about using an
在该流中将是对对象的引用。关于使用
Optional
可选的
is if we return an Optional from min or max,
是如果我们从最小或最大返回可选值，
or any other method, we know this will be
或任何其他方法，我们知道这将是
a valid reference. So it's not going to be null.
有效参考。因此，它不会为空。
So we return an Optional regardless. And then what it contains
因此我们无论如何都返回Optional。然后它包含的内容
is either null or a valid reference.
为null或有效的引用。
now we can use Options in different ways. So here's
现在我们可以以不同的方式使用选项。所以这是
what we would do in normal Java code
我们将在普通Java代码中执行的操作
if we want test whether something set
如果我们要测试是否设置了某些东西
and if it is then we want to do something. So here I'm saying
如果是的话，我们想做点什么。所以我在说
if x does not equal null, print x.  Well I could do that with an Optional
如果x不等于null，则打印x。好吧，我可以选择一个
simply by saying optional dot if present, and then passing
只需说出可选点（如果存在），然后通过
a lambda expression to represent what I want to do. So here I'm gonna say
一个lambda表达式来代表我想要做什么。所以在这里我要说
I want to print x. I can replace that with the method reference.
我想打印x。我可以将其替换为方法参考。
Or I can reference the method this -sorry- method
或者我可以引用此方法-sorry-方法
print which is in this object and just say this::print.
print在这个对象中，只说this :: print。
So does the same thing. Okay so that's,
同样的事情也是如此。好吧，那是
that's one use of an Optional. It's not terribly exciting,
这是Optional的一种用法。这并不令人兴奋，
but it allows us to eliminate that problem.
但这可以消除我们的问题。
But we might also have a situation where we want to
但我们可能还会遇到一种情况，
test whether x is valid,
测试x是否有效，
but also whether x meet some criteria. Here what I'm doing is saying
而且x是否满足某些条件我在这里说的是
if x does not equal null and x contains an
如果x不等于null并且x包含一个
a then we want to print x. Now
然后我们要打印x。现在
because we've gotten an and statement there, and because the
因为我们在那里有一个and语句，并且因为
test begins null is the first one, we don't have to worry about
测试开始null是第一个，我们不必担心
nullPointerException because if x does equal null
nullPointerException因为如果x等于null
we don't bother evaluating the second half of the and statement.
我们不必理会and语句的后半部分。
So that's okay. But we can do the same thing
所以没关系。但是我们可以做同样的事情
with our Optional. Now we can use filter.
与我们的可选。现在我们可以使用过滤器。
Again, it's the same kind of idea as we have
再说一次，这与我们的想法相同
with a stream. Remember an Option is like a stream of 0
与流。记住一个选项就像一个0流
or 1 elements. So in this case we'll take our Optional
或1个元素。因此，在这种情况下，我们将采用Optional
and then we'll pass it to filter and we use
然后我们将其传递给过滤器，然后使用
predicate, a lambda expression to represent math, saying
predicate，代表数学的lambda表达式，说
"Does x contain an a?". That way,
“ x是否包含a？”。那样，
if the Optional contains a null reference we have a stream of
如果Optional包含空引用，则我们有一个
0 elements.
0个元素。
it doesn't get pasted to filter. We don't bother doing anything. If
它不会被粘贴过滤。我们什么都不做。如果
it does contain invalid reference, we pause x to filter.
它确实包含无效的引用，我们暂停x进行过滤。
X then gets processed to look whether it contains a
然后处理X，看它是否包含一个
That will create a new Optional,
这将创建一个新的Optional，
which either contains null because x doesn't contain an a, or,
要么包含空值（因为x不包含a），要么，
it contains x because it does contain an a. If it does contain an a,
它包含x，因为它确实包含a。如果确实包含a，
we pass it to ifPresent and we print it out. So we have
我们将其传递给ifPresent并打印出来。所以我们有
a simpler version of thinking about code. We can get a bit further.
一种更简单的代码思考方式。我们可以走得更远。
We can do some translations using map.
我们可以使用地图进行翻译。
We may have a situation where we test to see if x is
我们可能会遇到一种情况，我们需要测试x是否为
not null. If it isn't null, them we're going to
不为空。如果不为null，我们将
manipulate x in some way. So will do
以某种方式操纵x。所以会做
trim x to remove any blank
修剪x以删除任何空白
characters and assign that to t. Then we'll test to see if t is greater than 0. And if it is then
字符并将其分配给t。然后，我们将测试t是否大于0。
we'll will print it out.
我们将把它打印出来。
Again we could do the same thing with our Optional.
同样，我们可以使用Optional做同样的事情。
In this case, we'll use a map.
在这种情况下，我们将使用地图。
So what we're gonna do here is say take a our Optional, if it eve exists,
所以我们要在这里做的是说采取“可选”（如果有的话），
as a reference. Pass it to map. In this case
作为参考。将其传递给地图。在这种情况下
we'll do mapping using the function of
我们将使用的功能进行映射
trim from string (method reference again). Then we'll pass that
从字符串中修剪（再次引用方法）。然后我们通过
to filter to determine whether the length
过滤以确定长度
of the string is greater than 0. That produces a new
的字符串大于0。这会产生一个新的
Optional which is either null
可选，为null
or valid reference. Depending on whether the predicate
或有效参考。取决于是否predicate
returns true or false. So if we do return a
返回true或false。所以如果我们返回一个
valid reference, we put that in the Optional. Go if present we print out
有效的引用，我们将其放在Optional中。如果有的话我们去打印
whatever t is. And then we can go even further.
不管是什么然后我们可以走得更远。
So let's say I have a method
所以说我有一个方法
which is called findSimilar that takes a string
称为findSimilar的字符串
as an argument and returns a string. But potentially findSimilar could return a
作为参数并返回一个字符串。但潜在地findSimilar可能会返回
null.
空值。
So to make that better we'll change
因此，为了更好，我们将改变
the method and we'll call it tryFindSimilar.
该方法，我们将其称为tryFindSimilar。
On this, rather than returning a string directly, it'll return
在此基础上，它将直接返回而不是直接返回字符串
Optional of type string. Remember the Optional
字符串类型的可选。记住可选
will contain a reference to whatever tryFindSimilar
将包含对任何tryFindSimilar的引用
actually does. Could be a null.
确实有。可以为null。
Or could be the actual string.
或者可以是实际的字符串。
So if you want to use that in an Optional,
因此，如果您想在Optional中使用它，
Then we run into a bit of a problem. Because if we want to do a to mapping
然后我们遇到了一个问题。因为如果我们想做一个to映射
using this new method then
然后使用这种新方法
what will happen is map will create a new Optional
地图将创建一个新的Optional
and put whatever the result of the function that he used as the
并把他用作
parameter inside that Optional. But tryFindSimilar already returns an Optional
可选参数。但是tryFindSimilar已经返回了Optional
So now we have an optional of type String contained
所以现在我们有一个包含String类型的可选
in Optional. So that's one too many Optionals.
在可选。因此，这是太多可选项。
To alleviate this problem
为了缓解这个问题
we can use flatMap. And flatMap
我们可以使用flatMap。和flatMap
will assume that the function that we're using
将假设我们正在使用的功能
doesn't need to be placed an Optional because it already
不需要放置Optional，因为它已经
returns an Optional. That way we just use the result of tryFindSimilar
返回Optional。这样，我们只使用tryFindSimilar的结果
which is an Optional of type String. And then we can use that
这是String类型的Optional。然后我们可以使用
directly. We don't have to worry about being an Optional contained
直。我们不必担心成为可选的包含
in another Optional. If we go back to our
在另一个Optional中。如果我们回到我们的
GPS code and we update that too use Optionals correctly,
GPS代码，我们也会更新为正确使用Optionals，
we can now see that in our GPSData class
现在我们可以在GPSData类中看到
our getPosition method is going to return Optional
我们的getPosition方法将返回Optional
of type Position. The Position class
位置类型。位置类
will have a method called getLatitude that will return an Optional
将具有一个名为getLatitude的方法，该方法将返回Optional
of type Latitude. And then the Latitude class
的类型。然后是Latitude类
will just have method called getDirection
只会有一个叫做getDirection的方法
that will return String. To use that
这将返回字符串。使用那个
what we do now is we say the direction is going to be
我们现在要做的是说方向将是
optional and, we first of all have to create an Optional
可选，我们首先必须创建一个可选
from out GPS data and
从GPS数据中
we use ofNullable to indicate that
我们使用ofNullable表示
GPSData could be a null, or it could be a valid reference.
GPSData可以为null，也可以为有效参考。
If we knew the GPS data was a valid reference
如果我们知道GPS数据是有效参考
we could just use optional dot of. But because we don't know
我们可以只使用可选的点。但是因为我们不知道
whether it's null or not, we use Optional dot ofNullable.
无论它是否为null，我们都使用Optional点ofNullable。
That way you don't get any problems.
这样，您就不会有任何问题。
We pass that into flatMap.
我们将其传递给flatMap。
With flatMap using the function
与flatMap一起使用的功能
which is the method reference to get position and we flatMap it again
这是获取位置的方法参考，我们再次将其平面映射
to get latitude from that position. Remember that both getPosition and
从那个位置获得自由度。请记住，getPosition和
getLatitude
getLatitude
return an Optional. So we don't want to include those
返回一个可选的。所以我们不想包括那些
in another Optional. We simply want poss that to the next
在另一个Optional中。我们只是想把它带到下一个
part of our chain of method calls. So we use flatMap
方法调用链的一部分。所以我们使用flatMap
so that we know getPosition and getLatitude will return optional.
这样我们知道getPosition和getLatitude将返回可选的。
And we then pass that to map.
然后我们将其传递给地图。
Map uses the getDirection method of Latitude,
地图使用Latitude的getDirection方法，
which does return a sSring so we need to
确实返回sSring，所以我们需要
put that inside an Optional. So the map will take the result of getDirection,
将其放在Optional中。因此地图将采用getDirection的结果，
put it inside a String and put in some Optional,
将其放在字符串中，并放入一些Optional中，
and then pass it to orElse. So that if
然后将其传递给orElse。因此，如果
the getDirection returns a null
getDirection返回null
then orElse will return None.
则orElse将返回无。
Otherwise we'll get the direction of
否则我们会得到
our particular latitude reading from the GPS.
我们从GPS读取的特定纬度。
If getDirection returns null, return None.  Otherwise
如果getDirection返回null，则返回None。除此以外
return an actual direction. And that solves our problem.
返回实际方向。这就解决了我们的问题。
So to summarize Section 7: you can see that the Optional class helps us to eliminate
所以总结一下第7节：您可以看到Optional类可以帮助我们消除
problems of nullPointerExceptions. We can use it in
nullPointerExceptions问题。我们可以在
in quite complex ways if you get into the idea of using flatMaps maps and
如果您想使用flatMaps地图和
filters and
过滤器和
and those sorts of things, in order to allow you to take
和类似的事情，以便让您
the results of a stream Optional,
流的结果可选，
and then process it post process it
然后处理它
and do things with it. So it is a very useful thing not just in time to streams
并用它做事。因此，这不仅是及时流媒体，而且是非常有用的事情
but also
但是也
outside streams as well. That brings us to the end of lesson 2
外流也是如此。这使我们到了第二课的结尾
So again, I'd like to just have a quick summary
再说一遍，我想简要介绍一下
of what we've dealt with in lesson 2. What things you should now
第二课中我们处理的内容
be aware of.
意识到。
So the streams API provides us
因此，流API为我们提供了
with a simple straightforward way of having a functional style of
具有一种简单易懂的函数式风格
programing in Java. Remember functional programming
用Java编程。记住函数式编程
is about having function calls linked together.
关于将函数调用链接在一起。
The streams API allows us to chain together method calls
流API允许我们将方法调用链接在一起
so that we can do effectively the same thing with Java.
这样我们就可以有效地用Java做同样的事情。
In terms of the streams that we create
就我们创建的流而言
we can on either create streams objects
我们可以创建流对象
or where it's appropriate we can create streams primitive types:
或者在适当的地方我们可以创建流原始类型：
int, long, double. That way we can avoid the problems
int, long, double。这样我们可以避免问题
of boxing and unboxing to improve the efficiency how
装箱与拆箱如何提高效率
the stream works. Structure upstream
该流有效。上游结构
is like a pipeline. One end of the pipeline you got source
就像一条管道。您获得源代码的管道的一端
you got some possible intermediate operations in the middle,
您在中间进行了一些可能的中间操作，
and then the other end your pipeline is a terminal operation
然后管道的另一端是终端操作
which creates either explicit result or some kind of side effect.
这会产生明显的结果或某种副作用。
A lot of the terminal operations
很多终端操作
return an Optional, so if we don't have any data on the InputStream
返回一个Optional，所以如果我们在InputStream上没有任何数据
we don't have to worry about null pointer references and we can take care that
我们不必担心空指针引用，我们可以注意
through the
通过
appropriate use all the Optional. Remember ofOptionals can be used
适当使用所有Optional。记住ofOptionals可以使用
outside streams API for many different situations
用于许多不同情况的外部流API
where you want to avoid null pointer exceptions.
您想避免空指针异常的地方。
And that is the end of lesson 2.
至此，第二课结束了。